gfi.org 2019-05-01

# Privacy Policy

                                  Privacy Policy
Last updated May 2018
Thank you for your interest in The Good Food Institute (GFI). Your privacy is important
to us and we are committed to protecting your data and your interactions with GFI. We
are dedicated to providing a safe place to collaborate, educate, and join in our mission.
Please read below for details regarding how we utilize the information you provide to us.
For users accessing this website from the European Union, this Privacy Policy also
provides instructions on how to request the removal of your data or a readout of your
data as required under the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”).
Please also note that this policy applies only to websites and publications maintained by
GFI and not to external sites or affiliated organizations and companies. Refer to the
privacy policies of the respective organizations and companies for more information.
How does GFI collect my information?
GFI may collect your information directly through submission forms on our webpages,
in partnership with third parties, or passively through digital tools including Cookies
and Pixels. For users visiting our webpage from the European Union, GFI relies on your
consent as a lawful basis for collecting your information. Please follow the instructions
contained in this Privacy Policy to withdraw consent or to limit our ability to receive
                                                                                          1

certain types of information through our digital tools or the tools of our third-party
partners.
Opportunities to submit information
There are various places on our websites and other publications (both online and print)
where you are able to enter personal information in order to receive information
relevant to your interests and be updated about important activity at GFI, including the
following:
    ● E-newsletter sign-up forms
    ● Our Talent Database and Entrepreneur Forms
    ● Volunteer sign-up forms
    ● Event registration
By submitting your contact information through these various forms, or through email
communications, you consent to receiving emails from GFI relating to your interests
and to receiving other content from GFI relating to important developments related to
our mission or to volunteer opportunities or similar activities.
Cookies
In addition to information that you submit, like most websites, GFI uses “cookies” to
remember some details about visitors, such as their language preferences. Cookies are
used for the limited purpose of facilitating your use of this website and to allow you to
access our content with ease. These are not used to store personal information and are
not tied to any personally identifiable information, such as your name or your IP
address. These cookies may, however, allow us to obtain basic information, such as your
general geographic location, the way that you reached our website, and your activity on
our website. GFI’s website may not honor “do not track” signals that it receives from
                                                                                          2

visitors’ web browsers unless honoring such requests is mandated by local law. GFI also
relies on information obtained from cookies to perform ongoing analysis and improve
our website and to tailor our content to your interests.
Pixels
GFI works with third-party partners such as Facebook and Google to tailor our content
to your preferences when you visit our websites through links in advertisements on our
third-party partners’ websites. This information, which may include language and
location information, allows us to work to customize our content and also helps guide
our decisions regarding the effectiveness of certain content so that we can display
content that you are interested in receiving. GFI also relies on information obtained
from pixels to perform ongoing analysis and improve our website and tailor our content
to your interests.
How is this information used?
Information supplied in contact forms is used to send you updates and information
about GFI and our programs, including events, activities, appeals, donation
opportunities, and news.
We also use information to improve our websites and campaigns. By collecting visitor
behavior statistics, we are able to measure interest in our various programs and use this
information to better serve you and make our communications more effective.
How can I stop providing this information?
If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple
procedure in most browsers that allows you to automatically decline cookies or be given
the choice of declining or accepting the transfer to your computer of a particular cookie
(or cookies) from a particular site. You can choose whether to accept cookies by
                                                                                          3

changing the settings on your browser or, depending on your jurisdiction, by managing
your tracking preferences as noted in a separately posted cookie statement or via a
posted cookie manager. If, however, you do not accept cookies, you may experience
some inconvenience in your use of the online services. For example, we may not be able
to recognize your computer, and you may need to log-in every time you visit. You also
may not receive advertising or other offers from us that are relevant to your interests
and needs. At this time, we do not respond to browser “Do-Not-Track” signals except in
jurisdictions where we are required to do so by law.
How can I request, correct, or delete my personal information?
GFI will respond to all requests to provide records of available information, correct
erroneous information, or delete personal information, which can be submitted by
sending an email with the request to our optimization team at ​dataprivacy@GFI.org​. We
will respond to all requests within the legally mandated timeframe.
How is my information protected?
GFI uses security protocols to ensure the privacy of your information. We do not sell,
trade, or share email addresses. We use industry standard SSL (secure socket layer)
technology to protect your information and provide a safe and secure environment for
online donations. GFI does not see, store, or retain credit card numbers. Credit card
information is submitted directly to Stripe, a third party that processes financial
transactions. For more information about the information security offered by Stripe, you
may visit their website at ​https://stripe.com​ and view their Terms of Service.
Your rights with respect to your personal information
You may have certain rights regarding your personal information, subject to local law.
These include the rights to access your personal information; correct the information we
hold about you; erase your personal information; restrict our use of your personal
                                                                                        4

information; object to our use of your personal information; withdraw your consent for
us to use your personal information, if applicable; receive your personal information in
a usable electronic format and transmit it to a third party (right to data portability); and
lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority (if applicable).
Unsubscribing from our mailing list and monthly highlights
If you are currently receiving regular emails from us and wish to unsubscribe, you may
do so by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of the emails. You may send your
request to unsubscribe from monthly highlights to ​dataprivacy@gfi.org​.
Notice for minors
Minors should not submit their personal information, such as their names, addresses,
phone numbers, or other personal identifying information, through this website. In the
event you have inadvertently submitted such information you can delete any content
you have posted by contacting GFI at ​dataprivacy@gfi.org​. You should be aware that the
removal of content may not ensure the complete or comprehensive erasure of that
information from the internet or third-party archives.
Additional questions and effective date
This policy is effective as of May 25, 2018, and may be amended from time to time. Any
amendments to our Privacy Policy will be posted as a notification on this page. If you
have questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at ​dataprivacy@gfi.org​.
If you would like to view or make changes to your personal information, please contact
us at ​dataprivacy@gfi.org​ ​and an GFI representative will be happy to assist you.
                                                                                            5
